that makes no sense rotate device is
that right
I don't know recording on my phone at
the moment I was doing yoga the obits do
you have access to you realized I hadn't
recorded my video today so I thought I
would just do here before taking the
track back calling this down on the bus
in Vancouver which can take forever I
mean there's so much snow and so don't
we think you know climate change because
I mean there's the polar vortex going on
there's a reason we've stopped calling
it global warming and started calling it
climate change because it's the changing
climate and it's extreme weather event
it's not just all about warming but how
we actually solve climate change is many
fold
I haven't taken notes it's something I
think about all the time sort of notes
with me
we need an access to the information we
need access to the science that
everybody can understand so that you
can't don't have this debate of like
it's a human causes is it not and so
that we can see okay yeah there's like
99% of science showing that it's human
caused or 90% of the science showing
that it's human caused 10% showing it
maybe it's something that humans don't
cause whether or not humans have caused
it we're gonna suffer the repercussions
so now we need a system to be able to
deal with environmental catastrophe that
we're definitely causing because we are
the ones creating the chemicals and
pumping them into the world and creating
the pollution but also if there's going
to be extreme weather we need to be able
to deal with that as well we need to be
able to have a system to problem-solve
from the ground up to be able to have
people not fall through the cracks and
so it's all interrelated because how we
solve climate changes how we solve
everything give people access to the
information so that solutions can come
from every anywhere give people the
ability to come together and create
solutions the tools to be able to do
that and anytime there is a new solution
be able being able to assess the
techniques SS to be able to assess it to
see how good it is compared to what we
have currently currently then yes let's
move forward with this all being
something
having an excess information and then an
actual report card but to actually see
where are we where do we need to get to
and how far along that process are we
that everyone can follow that isn't Fox
News or CNN or anyone else giving the
information that it's information we can
trust because people like us have gotten
together and said here's including
climates and iers and climate change
scientists who are like yes this is the
information here's here's everything we
would want to know about climate change
in the environment here's what we do
know here's what we don't know and I
let's move on with the task of actually
saving ourselves and the planet what do
we do if temperatures go up put them in
with temperatures go down what do we do
if there's if there are sea waters rise
how do we move people out of the sea
cities inland where they'll be safe
without destroying our planet do we not
how do we deal with the mass human
migration that happens because of
climate change and climate events
famines and whatnot and so the tools we
need the tools to be able to solve
climate change that we need for
everything else so to sell health care
but it's Helfer financial crisis is how
this all of it is access to information
that is trustworthy and accessible that
we can point back to so we don't need to
have the same old tired of being it
again and again and again and
constituents solutions instead of the
problem once we have a bigger
understanding of the problem then we
need to be able to have tools to be able
to actually accomplish solutions and
assess them instead of letting leaving
it up to government and/or industry then
we can actually move forward on projects
and see ok is this getting better
because a lot of what does happen in the
world right now is this idea that like
okay well I can't with the solution and
I'm doing the solutions of course it's
working well you have metrics to test it
like are we reversing climate change are
we taking more carbon out than they're
putting in and because that's what we
need to get to isn't in every solution
has to be able to do that but together
we need to be able to do that to be able
to actually look at the problem
logically and assess it quantitatively
and then see are we actually making a
better if we're dealing with poverty or
less people in poverty do we have more
being fed or we are we improving
people's lives instead of destroying
them
it's like that's what I metric we even
look at we just look at GDP we make more
money this year so this was just to do
my video for today I will do that this
topic in a more next time climate change
hits me snow today I'm just to leave
with a bare minimum snow it's like BC
snowstorm which is like this brave
sprinkly and like someone took icing
sugar and put it out but the city does
kind of shut down when that happens and
I can't drive what happens so it does
kind of